simons.ca 2013-10-03

# Simons | Women's Clothing, Men's Clothing, Accessories, Home Décor

We are serious about protecting your identity and personal information. Our privacy policy applies to the personal information we collect instore, through our website at [www.simons.ca](http://www.simons.ca/), and through our customer relationships. At La Maison Simons Inc., we respect our customers. We understand your concerns about privacy, so we have posted this privacy policy to inform you what personal information we collect, how it is treated, what choices you have regarding our use of your information and how you may access your personal information.

For more information about the Terms of Use for this site, please visit our legal page.

This Privacy Policy applies to personal information we collect at our stores, through our website located at [www.simons.ca](http://www.simons.ca/), and through other interactions with our customers.  

###  Collection and Use of Personal Information

You can browse in our stores or on our Website without giving us any personal information.

We may collect personal information when you:

  * Purchase, order, return or exchange merchandise;
  * Request to be on our email list or to receive other marketing communications;
  * Sign-up to receive a Simons catalog;
  * Register on our Website;
  * Apply for employment;
  * Participate in one of our contests or promotions or respond to a survey;
  * Submit a comment or question to customer service via e-mail or our live chat, or visit a customer service desk in one of our Stores.

Shopping at Simons: You do not have to provide us with any personal information when you purchase products and services for cash at one of our Stores. If you use a debit or credit card for any of your purchases, we collect your debit or credit card-related information and signature (in-store only) for the purposes of processing and administering your payment. For purchases made on our Website, we also collect your billing and shipping address, telephone address, email address and gift message (if provided) in order to deliver the products you ordered. We may also collect optional information such as your date of birth which we use to send you a birthday greeting.

When you return or exchange previously purchased merchandise in one of our Stores, you may be asked to give your name, address, and phone number. We collect this information to administer our loss prevention program, including to help detect and prevent fraud. For merchandise returns where a customer receives a refund on a debit or credit card, we will collect and use debit and credit-related information to process and administer the refund transaction.

Marketing Communications: When you sign up to receive our newsletter, catalogue or other promotional communications via mail or email, we may collect personal information such as your first and last name, email and/or mailing address (depending on method of delivery) and interests in order to provide you with the service you requested.  

We want to contact you only if you want us to. You are free to choose at any time not to receive our promotional communications by clicking the “Unsubscribe” button that appears at the bottom of our e-mails or by contacting us as set out in the “Unsubscribe” section below.

Online Registration: Some of the features available on our Website (such as the wish list and address book) may require you to register. When you register, we collect your first and last name, email address and a password that you select in order to provide and otherwise administer the service you requested. At the time you register online, we may ask your permission to send you future marketing information from Simons or its marketing partners. To withdraw your consent for such communications, contact us as set out in the “Unsubscribe” section below. 

Employment Opportunities at Simons: We may advertise employment opportunities on our Website. In connection with a job application or related inquiry, you may provide us with certain personal information about yourself (such as that contained in a resume, cover letter, or similar employment-related materials). We use this information to process and respond to your application for employment or related inquiry.

Contests, Promotions, Surveys: When you enter a contest, participate in a promotion, or respond to one of our surveys, we may collect your name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use this information to administer your participation in the contest or promotion and, for surveys, to understand our customers and enhance our product and service offerings, promotions and events. At the time you are entering the contest, promotion or survey, we may ask your permission to send you future marketing information from Simons or its marketing partners. To withdraw your consent for such communications, contact us as set out in the “Unsubscribe” section below

The "Send to a Friend" and other similar features on our Website permit you to send emails to others. This feature requires you to submit your name and email address, as well as the name and email address of the recipient. We do not use the names or email addresses submitted in these circumstances for any other purpose without the consent of you or the email recipient to do so.

Customer Service: When you submit a comment or question to customer service via e-mail or our live chat, or when you visit a customer service desk in one of our Stores, we may collect personal information such as your name, e-mail or mailing address and/or a phone number in order to respond to your comment or question. We also collect various types of information that you provide in order to allow us to answer your question.  

###  Disclosure of Personal Information

Except as otherwise set out herein, we will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer personal information about our customers to any third party without consent.

Service Providers: We may transfer your personal information to third parties who provide services on our behalf, such as process payments, host our Web site, send email or other communications on our behalf, run our contests and promotions, or analyze our advertising effectiveness. Your personal information may be stored and processed in the United States by our affiliates and other third party service providers.

These service providers are subject to a nondisclosure agreement and to other legal restrictions that govern their use of information we provide them and they are not authorized to use or disclose personal information for any purpose other than to provide services on our behalf or as otherwise required by applicable law. 

Legal: We and our service providers must give your personal information in response to a search warrant or any other legally valid inquiry or order or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as it is required by applicable law. 

Sale of Business: We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Simons or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.  

###  Website Information

When you visit our Website, we collect the Internet Protocol address of all visitors to our Website and related information such as the Internet browser you are using, the computer operating system you are using, time spent visiting the Web site, usage patterns within the Web site, and the domain name of the web site from which you linked to our site. We collect this information to help us understand and improve your experience on the Website.  

###  Cookies and Web Beacons

Our Website uses a technology called "cookies". A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. We use cookies on the pages on our Website where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable. If you have registered with our Website, these cookies help us identify you and may be necessary to provide you with products or services you request.  Cookies may also provide us or our service providers with information that we will use to personalize our Web site in accordance with your preferences. You may set your Web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. However, if you decide not to accept cookies from our Website, you may not be able to take advantage of all of the features of our Website. Our Website may also use a technology called "tracer tags" or "Web Beacons". This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Website. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor our Website for you and other future visitors to our Website.  

###  Deactivate Account/Unsubscribe

If you do not want to continue to receive e-mail from Simons or if you want to deactivate your account, please follow the steps outlined below to submit a request electronically or contact us at 1-877-666-1840 or by live chat.

Please note that every time we send you an email, we will give you the option to unsubscribe from our e-mail list, so you'll be able to stop receiving our e-mails at any time. You may also contact us as set out under “Contact Us” below.  Please allow 10 business days for your request to take effect. We appreciate your patience and understanding in giving us time to carry out your request.  

###  Unsubscribe from our communications :

Select the tab «Account».- Log in by entering your e-mail and password.- In the window «Your profile» click on the «Unsubscribe» button on the right.  

###  Deactivate your profile :

Select the tab «Account».- Log in by entering your e-mail and password.- At the bottom of the window «Your profile» you will find the link «Close your account».- Select «Change» and move your account to «Inactive».- Then, «Save».  

###  Security of personal information

We realize that our customers trust us to protect their personal information. We take that task seriously. We have implemented measures in an effort to safeguard the personal information in our custody and control, including only providing access to personal information to employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control.

To provide you with an increased level of security, online access to certain personal information may be protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. Simons will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, you should be aware that, unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be secure.  As a result, Simons does not represent, warrant or guarantee that personal information will be protected against loss, misuse or alteration and does not accept any liability for personal information submitted by you, nor for your or third parties’ use or misuse of personal information.

Below are some recommendations to help ensure that your online shopping is safe.

  * If you use a public computer, always close your session when you are done.
  * Do not disclose your passwords. Remember that somebody who knows your password can access your account.
  * When you create a password, use at least 8 characters – a combination of letters and numbers is the best. Don’t use dictionary words, your name, your e-mail address or any other personal information that can be easily obtained. It is also recommended to change your password often. If you need help, visit the “Account” page, click on “Your profile” tab and on the button “Modify” – change your password and “Save”.
  * Use a different password for your different accounts online.
  * Beware of unsolicited e-mails and unsolicited phone calls.

In addition, Simons will never contact you to ask you information about your credit card number or bank account. Information like this should be sent to Simons only when you do a transaction, by contacting Simons directly or by modifying your account online. If you receive a suspect e-mail with a link to update the information on your account, do not click on this link. Go directly into your account on [www.simons.ca](http://www.simons.ca/). If a stranger contacts you, sends you an unsolicited email or asks you to confirm or give your password or personal or banking information, ignore the request and contact us immediately.

For security reasons and to prevent fraud, orders paid by credit cards through this website will be accepted by Simons only if the billing name and address match the name and address on the credit card of the buyer. If the information does not match, your order will be refused, even if the transaction was pre-authorized by your bank. In that case, the amount of the order will be available for use only when the credit will be back in your account. This can take from three to five business days.  

###  About children

**Children Under 13**  
You can browse our Web site, but you cannot make a purchase. You also cannot become a registered user, or use any service that asks for personal information. Our site is not designed for children. We do not wish to collect personal information from children under 13. This policy is designed to protect children. 

If you register with us and we discover that you are under 13, we will delete your registration information. We will send you an email message if we do this. If you are under 13 and want to make a purchase, please ask a parent to place the order for you.  

###  Changes to our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal information practices. The revised Privacy Policy will be posted on the Website. We will treat your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Policy in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise consent.  

###  Contact Us

You may contact us with the contact information below at any time if you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy; wish to access, update and/or correct inaccuracies in our records of your personal information; to withdraw your consent for marketing communications; or have a complaint about the manner in which we treat your personal information.

Privacy Officer 20, CÔTE DE LA FABRIQUE, QUÉBEC, QC, G1R 3V9, CA (418) 692-3630
